

### 2510 Wittkop Way, Sacramento, CA 95825 | (C) 916-221-8331 | iq-m@att.net

www.linkedin.com/in/AmmarMira www.github.com/AmmarMira

# **Professional Summary**

With a strong technical skill-set, attention to detail, and one year of experience, I want to work as a front-end web developer where I could create digital magic and elevate user experience to the next level. I specialize in HTML5, CSS3 and Javascript.

## Skills Set

Markup Languages: HTML, DHTML, XHTML, HTML5, CSS, CSS3, Javascript and jQuery.

**Softwares:** Adobe Photoshop and Adobe Dreamweaver. **Framework:** Bootstrap 3, Foundation, jQuery and jQuery UI.

Server Technologies: Vagrant, Node.js, Apache, MAMP, and WAMP.

Version Management: Git, Github and Bitbucket.

**Other:** Grunt.js, Gulp.js, Node.js, npm, Bower, terminal, Iterm2 and Yoman. **Project Manager:** Asana, Basecamp, InVisionApp, Teamworkpm and JIRA.

-OS: Mac, Windows.

# Few Strong points from My Skill Set

- -Hands on experience in HTML5, CSS3 and Bootstrap.
- -Creating responsive websites from the ground up using CSS media queries.
- -Working with developers for resolving front end and CSS issues.
- -Ability of Writing Hand Code.
- -Experience in working with Java script and Jquery.

# **Work History**

**IT Technician** 01/2012 to 06/2012

Compu-Hub - Amman, Jordan

- Installing windows, software, applications, antivirus and patches
- Selling
- Front-end developer trainee

### Freelancer Front-End Web Developer

Husamui – Sacramento, CA

• Build websites using HTML, CSS and JavaScript languages.

**iPhone Technician** 03/2014 to 04/2015

Apple – Sacramento, California

- receive, restore, and check the whole phone.
- disassemble and assemble.
- recovery, visual inspection and paking.

### Jr. Front-End Web Developer

03/2015 to 04/2015

11/2014 to Current

Internet Marketing Bar – Rocklin, California

- Build websites using HTML, CSS and JavaScript.
- Find and fix issues.

### **Education**

High School Diploma: 2013

Jordan high school - Amman, Jordan

## **Certifications**

General cell phones repair course (IRD)